<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Deaf In The Cloud</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/</link><description>Recent content on Deaf In The Cloud</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 13:43:37 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deafinthecloud.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managed Workflows for Apache Airflow</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/m-w-apache-airflow/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 13:43:37 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/m-w-apache-airflow/</guid><description>See the announcement: Managed Workflows for Apache Airflow (MWAA).
Let&amp;rsquo;s start by asking what is Apache Airflow and why it plays an important part in automating the data flow in your business? Airflow is a standardized tool and framework that gives you visibility to your data flow end-to-end from ingestion to output (or multiple times over). It has a great graphical view showing users status of each workflow called DAG (Directed Acyclic Graphs).</description></item><item><title>Attending the Disability:IN Conference 2020 (virtually)</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/disability-in-conference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 11:55:58 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/disability-in-conference/</guid><description>Was about to head to Chicago for the Disability:IN conference, however due to the pandemic, the conference is now held virtually. While the number of speakers and plenaries may not be as great as if it was held in person, it still looks like a great lineup of speakers and companies making their presence known, in other words, holding up their &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re Hiring!&amp;rdquo; signs.
DAY ONE Started off with some words of encouragement for companies to join the Disability Equality Index also known as the DEI.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting Aws Deployments</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/troubleshooting-aws-deployments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 13:37:48 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/troubleshooting-aws-deployments/</guid><description>Deaf in the Cloud hosted by Robert Koch presents Troubleshooting AWS Deployments with Darren Weiner. Imagine for a minute you&amp;rsquo;re working with a cloud provider and provisioning features left and right; all of a sudden someone else runs a cloud formation script and broke something! We will do a deep-dive into a typical AWS VPC design and discussing well-architected designs. There&amp;rsquo;ll be a live demostration, and if you have your own AWS account, you can follow along.</description></item><item><title>Participating in a Jefferson Frank whitepaper project</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/jefferson-frank-project/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 13:47:29 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/jefferson-frank-project/</guid><description>Global leading AWS recruiter, Jefferson Frank, recently got in touch with me about an opportunity for an important project they were working on. In response to the Covid-19 crisis, they have collated expert advice from leading AWS Heroes and professionals into an industry whitepaper, of which I am proud to say I am part of.
The whitepaper covers five common challenges many are struggling with at this moment: cost saving, data security, remote working, growing at scale, and business continuity.</description></item><item><title>Using C# With AWS</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/using-c-sharp-with-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 13:37:33 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/using-c-sharp-with-aws/</guid><description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m doing a series on how C# works with AWS databases. AWS has 12 different databases all under different categories. Plagarizing the chart promiently displayed on the AWS Database page, I&amp;rsquo;ll go through each serverless and managed database one and see how my preferred language, C#, works. If you REALLY want it done in Python too, I can do that for you.
Database Types Use cases AWS service Relational Traditional applications, ERP, CRM, e-commerce Aurora, RDS, RedShift [NoSQL](#NoSQL) High-traffic web apps, e-commerce systems, gaming applications, content management, catalogs, user profiles DynamoDB, DocumentDB In-memory Coming soon.</description></item><item><title>Taking the AWS Certificate Exam Online</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/taking-online-exam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 13:37:25 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/taking-online-exam/</guid><description>I was about to schedule an AWS certification exam when everything was on hold due to the desire to maintain social distancing and keeping everyone healthy and safe. Regardless of your views, it&amp;rsquo;s important to play it safe rather than risking our lives especially when there are many unknowns involving COVID-19. In light of the situtation, it&amp;rsquo;s understandable that all exam centers were closed.
When I heard that AWS Training &amp;amp; Certifications in partnership with Pearson VUE had announced they will open up online testing, I immediately booked an exam two weeks out!</description></item><item><title>Speed of Data</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/speed-of-data/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 13:12:21 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/speed-of-data/</guid><description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about this topic for quite some time and while I&amp;rsquo;m putting this into this blog, it is a small part of a larger discussion. When we design and implement business systems, your eye is always on the workflow process and getting data from Point A to Point B as quickly and accurately as possible. Accuracy of the data is a business necessity and we have many ways to do this.</description></item><item><title>re:Invent 2019</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/reinvent-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 13:39:17 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/reinvent-2019/</guid><description>Venetian, Las Vegas, Nevada December 1-6
What. A. Week! That pretty much sums it up. This was my third re:Invent, first as a AWS Data Hero. The week started with the flight in, and it&amp;rsquo;s been pretty much non-stop from there. On the flight home, I actually nodded off, and I&amp;rsquo;m the type of person who cannot sleep while moving. That&amp;rsquo;s in addition to returning from a long vacation driving across western states bypassing a snowstorm and high winds for two days just to get home to make my Las Vegas flight the next day.</description></item><item><title>Developers Influencers Summit</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/developers-influencers-summit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 13:37:21 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/developers-influencers-summit/</guid><description>Westin Seattle August 19-21
It was the best of times, it was the worst of times, it was the age of wisdom, it was the age of foolishness, it was the epoch of belief, it was the epoch of incredulity, it was the season of Light, ... Some of you might remember the above paragraph is taken from the start of A Tales of Two Cities by Charles Dickens written in 1859.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to AWS Lambda</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/intro-to-aws-lambda/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 13:37:41 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/intro-to-aws-lambda/</guid><description>Tuesday July 23rd, 2019 - 5:30pm EST
Thank you for attending the talk! Below are recording, slides, and python code. Recording
Slides
Code
Presented by Robert Koch
Lambda is one of the core services from AWS (Amazon Web Services). Robert will introduce you to the workflow you can use to develop compute functions that usually ties components together whether they&amp;rsquo;re on AWS or not. AWS competitors, Azure Functions and Google Cloud Functions, both have similar development workflow and cost as Lambdas.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Managed Databases</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/cloud-managed-databases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 13:37:21 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/cloud-managed-databases/</guid><description>In many organizations right now, I see and hear of pushbacks from DBAs (Database Administrators) in moving stuff into cloud-based managed databases such as RDS or Azure databases. Managed databases does cost more and the cloud providers aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid to admit it: they&amp;rsquo;re showing you a straight flush before you even start the ante. It shows they&amp;rsquo;re confident of the value managed databases brings to an organization.
Database Administrators are usually on call 24/7 and they&amp;rsquo;re paid very well because of that.</description></item><item><title>Moving databases to the cloud</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/moving-databases-to-the-cloud/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 11:20:18 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/moving-databases-to-the-cloud/</guid><description>In many organizations right now, I see and hear of pushbacks from DBAs (Database Administrators) in moving stuff into cloud-based managed databases such as RDS or Azure databases. Managed databases does cost more and the cloud providers aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid to admit it: they&amp;rsquo;re showing you a straight flush before you even start the ante. It shows they&amp;rsquo;re confident of the value managed databases brings to an organization.
Database Administrators are usually on call 24/7 and they&amp;rsquo;re paid very well because of that.</description></item><item><title>Data Stacks in the Cloud</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/data-stacks-in-the-cloud/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 14:00:24 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/data-stacks-in-the-cloud/</guid><description>The talk has adjourned. Thanks all for your support!! Photos below.
Presented by Adam Stone, Ph.D.
blog
Data is ever-increasing and increasingly scattered across multiple app databases and SaaS services, while business teams still expect quick answers to their data questions. Traditional databases are bursting at the seams, and running SQL scripts on these databases to extract-transform-load data &amp;amp; produce business metrics (KPIs) takes up more resources and time. To address these challenges, a data stack ecosystem has sprouted, centered around cloud-based data warehouses (Amazon Redshift, Snowflake, Google BigQuery).</description></item><item><title>What is the cloud? Why is it important?</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/what-is-the-cloud/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 13:37:40 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/what-is-the-cloud/</guid><description>The cloud is a huge paradigm shift compared to your usual software development cycles. Imagine for a minute you have a requirement to build an API that customers would pull data from. You would fire up your favorite IDE, and build say a Swagger UI, and then deploy on whatever web server you already have. Rules are set in the software and there may be some custom validation and so on.</description></item><item><title>FAQs</title><link>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/faqs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 13:37:14 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://deafinthecloud.com/posts/faqs/</guid><description>Deaf in the Cloud &amp;ndash; this is a virtual user group that encompasses all deaf and signers into one spot to give presentations on a topic of your choosing, give each other feedback, help our career trajectories, and simply have a good time with the technology we know and love! I do want us to focus on cloud development, data science, and serverless technologies since I&amp;rsquo;d like us to follow industry trends for better knowledge transfer and leveraging our skills to jump into upcoming technologies.</description></item></channel></rss>